LABELS
Labels are used to sort and describe issues and pull requests. Some labels are usually reserved for one or the other, though most labels may be applied to both.

New issues will receive at least one label and a milestone, and new pull requests will receive at least one label. Except for the functional area and functional group label categories, issues will generally receive only up to one label per category.

TYPE
Issues are categorized into one of several types. Type labels are almost never used for pull requests. GitHub treats pull requests like issues in many ways, so a pull request could be considered an issue with an implicit Pull Request type label applied.

Feature - The issue is a request for new functionality including changes, enhancements, refactors, etc.

Bug - The issue documents broken, incorrect, or confusing behavior. This label is always accompanied by a severity label.

Duplicate - The issue is a duplicate of another feature request or bug report.

Upstream Bug - The issue is a result of an upstream issue.

Question - The issue is more of a question than a request for new features or a report of broken features, but can sometimes lead to further discussion or changes of confusing or incongruous behavior or documentation.

Expected Behavior - The issue is a bug report of intended functionality.

PRIORITY
An issue's priority is relative to its functional area. If a bug report, for example, about gitfs indicates that all users of gitfs will encounter this bug, then a P1 label will be applied, even though users who are not using gitfs will not encounter the bug. If a feature is requested by many users, it may be given a high priority.

P1 - The issue will be seen by all users.

P2 - The issue will be seen by most users.

P3 - The issue will be seen by about half of users.

P4 - The issue will not be seen by most users. Usually the issue is a very specific use case or corner case.

SEVERITY
Severity labels are almost always only applied to issues labeled Bug.

Blocker - The issue is blocking an impending release.

Critical - The issue causes data loss, crashes or hangs salt processes, makes the system unresponsive, etc.

High Severity - The issue reports incorrect functionality, bad functionality, a confusing user experience, etc.

Medium Severity - The issue reports cosmetic items, formatting, spelling, colors, etc.

FUNCTIONAL AREA
Many major components of Salt have corresponding GitHub labels. These labels are applied to all issues and pull requests as is reasonably appropriate. They are useful in organizing issues and pull requests according to the source code relevant to issues or the source code changed by pull requests.

Execution Module

File Servers

Grains

Multi-Master

Packaging Related to packaging of Salt, not Salt's support for package management.

Pillar

RAET

Returners

Runners

SPM

Salt-API

Salt-Cloud

Salt-SSH

Salt-Syndic

State Module

Tests

Transport

Windows

ZMQ

FUNCTIONAL GROUP
These labels sort issues and pull requests according to the internal SaltStack engineering teams.

Core - The issue or pull request relates to code that is central or existential to Salt itself.

Platform - The issue or pull request relates to support and integration with various platforms like traditional operating systems as well as containers, platform-based utilities like filesystems, command schedulers, etc., and system-based applications like webservers, databases, etc.

RIoT - The issue or pull request relates to support and integration with various abstract systems like cloud providers, hypervisors, API-based services, etc.

Console - The issue or pull request relates to the SaltStack enterprise console.

Documentation - The issue or pull request relates to documentation.

STATUS
Status labels are used to define and track the state of issues and pull requests. Not all potential statuses correspond to a label, but some statuses are common enough that labels have been created for them. If an issue has not been moved beyond the Blocked milestone, it is very likely that it will only have a status label.

Cannot Reproduce - The issue is a bug and has been reviewed by a SaltStack engineer, but it cannot be replicated with the provided information and context. Those involved with the bug will need to work through additional ideas until the bug can be isolated and verified.

Confirmed - The issue is a bug and has been confirmed by a SaltStack engineer, who often documents a minimal working example that reproduces the bug.

Fixed Pending Verification - The issue is a bug and has been fixed by one or more pull requests, which should link to the issue. Closure of the issue is contingent upon confirmation of resolution from the submitter. If the submitter reports a negative confirmation, this label is removed. If no response is given after a few weeks, then the issue will be assumed fixed and closed.

Info Needed - The issue needs more information before it can be verified and resolved. For a feature request this may include a description of the use cases. Almost all bug reports need to include at least the versions of salt and its dependencies, the system type and version, commands used, debug logs, error messages, and relevant configs.

Pending Changes - The pull request needs additional changes before it can be merged.

Pending Discussion - The issue or pull request needs more discussion before it can be closed or merged. The status of the issue or pull request is not clear or apparent enough for definite action to be taken, or additional input from SaltStack, the submitter, or another party has been requested.

If the issue is not a pull request, once the discussion has arrived at a cogent conclusion, this label will be removed and the issue will be accepted. If it is a pull request, the results of the discussion may require additional changes and thus, a Pending Changes label.

won't-fix - The issue is legitimate, but it is not something the Salt core team is currently able or willing to fix or implement. Issues having this label may be revisited in the future, or solved by a Salt community member.

TEST STATUS
These labels relate to the status of the automated tests that run on pull requests.

has-failing-test - The PR currently has one or more failing tests that prevent the PR from being merged.

Needs Testcase - The PR has code changes, but lack any automated tests. These PRs need automated tests written before they may be merged.

OTHER
These labels indicate miscellaneous issue types or statuses that are common or important enough to be tracked and sorted with labels.

Awesome - The pull request implements an especially well crafted solution, or a very difficult but necessary change.

Help Wanted - The issue appears to have a simple solution. Issues having this label should be a good starting place for new contributors to Salt.

Regression - The issue is a bug that breaks functionality known to work in previous releases.

Story - The issue is used by a SaltStack engineer to track progress on multiple related issues in a single place.

Stretch - The issue is an optional goal for the current sprint but may not be delivered.

ZD - The issue is related to a Zendesk customer support ticket.

<Release> - The issue is scheduled to be implemented by <Release>. See here for a discussion of Salt's release codenames.